Alright, so let us start off looking over some of the materials that we will use for these basic dings, you know.
Obviously, it is a step process.
What you want to do first is you want to prep and fill the ding.
And, for that what we will use is just any kind of normal, you know, mat knife that you could get from Home Depot.
Any straight edge, you know, even a razor blade will work in some of these instances.
You definitely want sand paper.
Golden rule about surfboard repair, resin will not bond to anything that is not prepped which means it has to be coarse and sanded.
So, if you think you can just pour the resin in the hole and it will bond, it will not.
At least sand it first.
Resin will bond to it.
That is what sand paper is for.
You got one twenty, two twenty.
The prepping usually starts with the fifty grit, which is a much more coarse sand paper.
You can find that at any, you know, home improvement store or Home Depot.
I mean, all of that stuff.
The second, you obviously you need fiberglass and resin.
That is over here.
Gloves.
You definitely want to use gloves when it comes to using these materials.
What we have is, this is lamination resin.
You could get that at any kind of plastic store.
Surf shops actually carry most of this ding repair stuff nowadays.
After the lam resin, there is hot coat resin.
Which is surfacing agent resin, which is sanding resin.
And, all that that is is laminating resin with a surfacing agent in it that you add.
But, obviously you could buy it as a hot coat.
Brushes to apply the resin, you know.
We got squeegees to squeegee out the resin after you saturate it.
And then, obviously you need acetone to clean your tools and yourself.
We've got fiberglass, which is obviously really important.
This is a four ounce fiber glass.
And, what you do is, you know, you use the resin to apply the fiberglass and get it to bond to the surf board.
And then, this is what is called Q Cell, or micro balloons.
And, what it is it is just a finely chopped fiber glass.
And it, what I call it is a surf board bondo, you know what I mean.
And, that is what you are going to do.
You are going to mix it laminating resin, and you are going to fill that in.
And, it is just going to take up the space that was taken away from the surf board.
All ding repairs, the fiber glass that you put on is actually on top of the surface.
Once you get it back to its normal state, that is when you do your structural damage, you know.
And, apply those products.
From our tools and materials, let us get into the real safety part of this process.